If it's all right, I'd like to
request an audience
with the Duke.
And I'd prefer
to speak with him. Alone.
There's something I need
you to tell
me before I can finish my work.
The lady in the portrait.
May I know her name?
And why is that necessary?
If I'm going to give her form,
then I need to learn
everything I can about her.
Things that I can't
tell from the portrait.
And then you'll succeed
for sure. I couldn't say.
Such a question intrudes upon
my most private of memories.
If you disturb what I've
left in the past.
And cause me more pain.
Only to fail,
you'll pay with your life.
Are you prepared for that?
I'm not prepared to die.
Because I've
made a promise
to a precious friend.
I have things left to say.
That's why I won't die.
So I am confident
that I'll be able to create the
peace you have been hoping for.
It's Christina. Christina. But
isn't that a human name? It is.
And what is her proper
fairy name? Laila. Shieldhill.
But that is so different. Why
wouldn't you use her true name?
Because she preferred it
that way. She wanted
to be called by a human name
and asked me to give her one.
That day,
she'd only just been born.
She looked out idly over
the waves that had birthed her.
I couldn't bear
the idea of someone
else catching her
and possibly doing her
harm. So I brought her here.
So where is Christina now?
Dead and gone.
It's been a year and a half.
He was in love. And even now
that she's passed away
somewhere deep in his heart,
he still calling out for her.
I heard his grace
had been acting strange.
But he's worse than I thought.
Also,
why isn't the lady Christina
with him anymore? His lover.
And a fairy.
Does she have blue hair?
Yes, indeed.
Did you see her there?
Only a portrait.
That's why the girl stayed.
To make him
a piece that resembles
her.
But you didn't see Christina.
Ah,
ciao. How long do fairies live?
If they're born out of the sea?
Their lives are unstable
by nature, so it varies.
Some stay alive for hundreds
of years, others for only a few.
But for those ones,
there's a fix.
Sugar confections can help them.
Most pieces
aren't powerful enough
to extend the fairies life.
I suppose it could be done
with something that you made,
but it would only add on a few
weeks or months. So that's it.
Lady Christina's disappeared.
That must be why he's.
Now, why would a human
be upset over that?
They just buy another companion
ferry and all is right again.
But she wasn't
a companion fairy. She
cannot be replaced,
not by anyone.
She was always saying
that water fairies
can never be sure of how
long they're going to live.
All this time,
I've been missing the point.
But now I know what
the Duke truly desires.
Would it be all right with you
if I brought my tools in here, sir?
I'd like to perform my work
in your presence.
I'll ask you questions about
Lady Christina to give her form.
I can't imagine how much suffering
the Duke has endured alone.
It wasn't fair. His house didn't
rebel against house mills,
and they fought for His
Majesty King Edmund the Second.
Despite that, the royal family laid
claim to their trade profits.
What's more, they forced Auburn to
make a monthly courtesy visit.
After all of that cruel treatment,
anyone would be resentful,
and the only one who soothed
his anger was her.
She took his contempt
upon herself. That doesn't
sound like such
a happy existence.
Yes,
but I believe she was happy.
I've made many sugar confections
for the Duke of Phylax,
and it's my understanding that
he gave each of them to her.
She said herself
that for his sake,
she'd like to live
just a little longer.
For the Duke's sake.
He was probably
afraid that something like
this would happen.
What's wrong?
Viscount sir. It appears that
the Earl soldiers
are just up ahead.
Hateful old man.
Earl of Downing. Oh, Mercury.
I see your attempt
at persuasion was
all for naught. So you knew.
You've had ties with him since
before you were made Viscount?
I was always aware of that fact.
That said,
you will interfere no more.
We shall quell the last
spark of rebellion.
I'll stand down. But that Anne
Halford, she's in there too.
Really? That's unfortunate. One can only
hope she's hidden herself well.
But, sir.
That girl. You there? One of
your acquaintances, I presume.
It was captured by one
of the cavalry.
Please give it a look. Hey.
Whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa.
Uh, hello? Mithril. Leopard.
It appears he ate
all of the soup
in that container while he was
hiding. No, that's not it.
Well, I mean, I did,
but it's not like that.
I was working hard
to fulfill my mission,
but then I started to get hungry.
What are you talking about?
Right. Of course.
I came looking for
you so that we could go
and help Anne.
Why is that? Because Anne
is calling out for you,
and she wants you
to go back there.
So you need to hurry, you fool.
She was the one who
told me to leave.
Do you seriously believe
that she wanted you to go away?
That the reason Anne
said those hurtful
things to you is because
Jonas threatened her?
He. What?
Jonas took my wing and said
that he'd crush it if Anne
didn't do what he told her to.
And once you were gone,
he used it to make his escape.
Anne's been crying her eyes
out ever since. You left.
She stayed in.
The castle to work on
that silly sugar confection.
The Duke of Felix
is saying that he won't
let her leave until she creates
the perfect piece for him.
And now Anne's being
really stubborn about it.
That idiot. Huh?
Hey, you can't trap me in here.
Here, I'll get him later.
Let me out of.
One, two, three. Well,
should I look after this thing?
A thing I am the splendorous
me thoroughly.
So I'll descend.
What are you planning?
I'll make it look just
like Lady Christina.
Her height features,
her expression. Everything.
If you don't
mind me asking this,
when you think about
Lady Christina, what's
the most common situation
that you picture her.
When I think
about a certain someone,
I'd say he's usually in a sour
mood and looking
down his nose at me.
Leaning against the wall, looking quite relaxed
and of course she smiling.
Thank you.
Your Grace.
Yes. Still,
there are troops outside, sir.
300 of them there.
The Earl of Downing's forces.
And they're demanding
that you surrender the castle.
And unfortunately, they
are taking you into custody.
They can wait.
I want to witness this.
Why would the Earl of Downing
want to arrest you, sir?
I haven't been to Lewiston
for a year and a half.
They'll say they question
my loyalty, but it's
just an excuse to attack me.
That's terrible. You don't deserve. That.
It is not your affair.
Now focus on your creation.
I just
don't understand why
you'd never understand.
Having all your dignity
stripped away. Being forced
to live your life in such a
humiliating manner.
Only she understood me.
In the Duke's eyes,
Lady Christina was all he had.
And now she's vanished
into thin air.
So he feels like he's alone
in the world. He's suffering.
Hmm. I'll make it.
I'll give his grace.
The one thing he cares about.
I want this piece to show
his feelings just as they are.
I'm taking her back.
Why are you.
Is this a dream?
Your idiocy is astounding.
Saw me through lid pod
explained everything to me.
You understand now?
So I'm sorry, I swear.
Don't apologize. What matters
now is that we're leaving.
But what
about the sugar confection?
I will not allow her
to leave this castle.
She will remain
with me until she
creates the perfect
sugar confection that I desire.
All right, then,
I'll cut you down
where you stand.
Wait a minute. Please.
Listen to me, your Grace. I'll
stay here and continue my work.
So, are you insane? Not at. All.
I still want to create a sugar
confection of that fairy.
I don't understand.
I said I would. I need to,
but this castle is surrounded
by soldiers.
If they attack it, you could be
killed. That's true.
It's not safe.
Yes, I know that. But still, I
refuse to leave
my work unfinished.
There's such a pain.
Fine, then make it.
I'll stay here to.
Is that all right, sir?
Yes. Of course. No work.
It is rather close, but the eyes
are the wrong color.
The silver and translucent
whenever the light strikes them.
It's only an object.
What's the point
in making it a perfect match?
When a living being gazes upon an
object and the energy condenses.
A fairy is born. So if I gaze
at this for long enough,
something may be born from it.
Don't you believe that's possible?
I see
you're hoping that this is a way
for Lady Christina to be reborn, right?
Have you ever seen the moment
a fairy disappears,
her form dissolved into
motes of light
and vanished into the air?
Right before my eyes.
Which means if
I can give her form,
she'll be able to return
to what she once was.
It won't work.
The dead cannot live again.
Despite how much you pray
or how many tears you cry.
And even if something was born,
it wouldn't be her.
It'd just be some warped
and wretched monster.
I forbid you
to say another word.
But it's true. Stop it! Shel!
So time's run out.
Please forgive me.
What are you doing?
I think I can make them silver.
You want to work
at a time like this?
The man is mad. You don't need
to play along with his
delusions. It's not for.
Him. Sugar confections
are my work. This
is the only thing
that I can take
pride in. It's my one skill.
Then you're an idiot.
I probably am,
but still. I want to do this.
If that's your. Wish. Work till
you're satisfied. I'll wait.
The Duke of Felix is upstairs.
Sorry.
But I won't
be letting you through.
Is that the Duke's warrior fairy? Stop
what you're doing! The viscount.
We have permission
from the Earl of Downing. Ciao.
I'm aware that you ran
off to go rescue Anne.
But I don't see why
you're protecting Albert.
That's not what
I'm doing at all.
But for now,
I can't let anyone through.
If we take too long, it'll
look like he's resisting us.
And that doesn't help Auburn's
case. Please stop. I'm sorry,
but this is what she wishes.
Right here.
In this silver sugar.
I beg you, please appear.
I see her.
Christina.
Otteson.
I never asked for your name.
I. Of course.
My name is Anne Halford, sir.
This is exactly what I wanted.
Halford.
I realized that my
desire might have been
foolish,
but nevertheless I wanted it.
I needed to see her again.
No one's proven it impossible.
If you keep gazing
at that statue and think
fondly of Lady Christina,
then eventually something
might come of it.
Or it might not. But there's
still no proof that it couldn't.
We may not mean that,
but it is comforting.
The crest I promised. I want you
to take this and return
to your fairy friend. Now.
Hartford.
You certainly are
a magnificent sugar artisan.
Shell.
Or shell?
No.
Um. Thank you for catching me.
You're all right.
Good. You. What are
you doing at the Duke's castle?
I don't have time to explain it,
but I've come to take the Duke
into custody. Is he still here?
I just gave him my work.
I see. Let's go.
What's wrong?
Just be still for now. I.
Don't frighten me like that.
I'm sorry. I was just doing what
a sugar artisan is supposed to.
And.
Huh? My name. That's the second
time I've heard you use it.
Really? So you've been counting?
Yes. It makes me happy.
Listen. I want you to stay by my
side from now on. Would you?
We're back, ma'am.
I heard the whole story, dear.
You were amazing.
Amazing. You made
the Duke Sugar confection.
It certainly was a shock to hear
that he'd
been taken into custody.
Everyone was predicting that his
punishment would be harsh.
Turns out he was
only sentenced to
living in solitude
under the Earl.
I thought that was
very merciful. And rumor
says it was
all thanks to the sugar
confection you crafted for him,
young lady.
I suppose there's
something to be said
for the belief that they
bring good fortune.
Are you done praying? Are. Yes.
We hope to accept the deaths
of our loved ones,
and we humbly pray
that those of us who
remain alive can someday
be free of our sorrow.
Hey, did you see that food stand
over there?
Everything looks so delicious.
Let's go and get some dinner.
Follow me. Shall we?